var quiz = [{"answers": ["women\u2019s empowerment", "scarce resources", "technology", "population"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Neo-Malthusians view _______ as the main limit of population growth."}, {"answers": ["Result\u00a0of Indias sterilization program in the 1950s.", "Womens empowerment", "Higher levels of education and literacy.", "Greater access to reproductive health care."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are reasons why the fertility rate is low in Kerala, India, except:"}, {"answers": ["Esther Boserup", "Thomas Malthus", "Barry Commoner", "Paul Ehrlich"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which theorist stated the following:\u00a0 \u201cThe Poor Laws of England tend to depress the general condition of the poor\u2026 they may be said, therefore, to create the poor which they maintain.\u201d"}, {"answers": ["Decrease", "Increase", "Leveling out", "Surge"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "After a period of economic transition and regulations, development is predicted to lead to a ___________________ in environmental impacts."}, {"answers": ["Disease", "Innovation", "Famine", "War"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Malthus believed that a natural correction to overpopulation includes all of the following except what?"}, {"answers": ["1700", "1800", "2000", "1400"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "World population did not reach 1 billion people until approximately what year?"}, {"answers": ["Esther Boserup", "Thomas Malthus", "Barry Commoner", "Paul Ehrlich"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "_______ argued that technology leads to greater environmental impact than population."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Devleoping countries (overall), have a much higher fertility rate than indutrialized countries."}, {"answers": ["Positive", "Negative", "Minimal", "Co-dependent"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Development initially has a large ___________ impact on the environment."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The demographic transition model shows population growth as a function of resource scarcity."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The fertility rate is the average number of children born to a woman during her reproductive years."}, {"answers": ["More petrochemical, fertilizer and pesticide use will negatively affect the environment.", "Increased use of energy for all of the farm equipment, transportation and manufacturing processes will have negative impacts on the environment.", "There will be different (more negative)\u00a0impacts on local communities compared to distant markets.", "Increased food supplies will be distributed more evenly across the world than before."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "All of the following are critiques of the Green Revolution and the Cornucopian Theory, except what?"}, {"answers": ["Technology", "Consumerist", "Sustainability", "Affluence"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The term that describes how many goods per capita are consumed in an area or country, or the total production in the country, is what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "An application of the I=PAT formula would be the ecological footprint."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Carrying capacity is the maximum number of people that a system can sustain over a period of time, assuming a particular lifestyle."}, {"answers": ["Neo-Malthusians", "Malthusians", "Cornucopians", "Feminists"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which group of people would agree with the statement that \"the more people, the more ideas we receive and the more solutions that will be generated\"?"}, {"answers": ["Green Revolution", "Induced intensification", "Ecological footprint", "Cornucopianism"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The idea that increased food demand leads to technological innovation that increases food production on the same amount of available land is known as what?"}, {"answers": ["It ignores the benefits of cornucopian thinking.", "It advocates for restricting mens education.", "It directs policy action, blame, and social control onto women and their bodies.", "It discounts the ability of politicians to manage environmental impacts through good public policy."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which of the following is a criticism of population-centered thinking?"}, {"answers": ["Does not help us identify sustainable limits regarding individual or composite impacts.", "Does not show the relationship between affluence and technology as it relates to the population.", "Does not provide support for decision-making or recognize historical or contextual factors such as beliefs, attitudes or politics.", "Assumes that impacts are proportional, but some environmental systems show non-linear characteristics."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which of the following is not a given critique of the rationale behind the I=PAT equation?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Most developed nations would fit into the\u00a0second stage of the demographic transition model."}, {"answers": ["Green Revolution", "an environmental Kuznets curve", "an ecological footprint", "a carrying capacity"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The area of the earth\u2019s surface that would be required to support a population based on the number of resources needed to sustain a particular lifestyle is known as _______."}, {"answers": ["Political systems need to be overhauled.", "Increase educational resources to the wealthy.", "People should exercise moral restraint.", "Increase use of welfare programs to assist the poor."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "What would Malthus suggest as a way to slow population growth?"}, {"answers": ["birth rates are high and death rates are high.", "birth rates are high and death rates are low.", "birth rates are\u00a0low and death rates are low.", "fertility rates are low."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Stage I in the demographic transition model describes a situation in which:"}, {"answers": ["production, affluence, and tradition.", "population, affluence, and technology.", "population, affordability, and technology.", "population, affordability, and territory."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The IPAT equation explains environmental impact as a function of:"}, {"answers": ["Increased population numbers", "Induced Intensification", "Green Revolution", "Decreased fertility rate"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "All of the following lead to greater crop yields under the Cornucopian Theory, except what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "High levels of womens education and literacy are associated with lower total fertility rates."}, {"answers": ["Ecological Footprint", "Demographic Transition Model", "Environmental Kuznets Curve", "I=PAT Equation"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The \"Forest Transition Theory\" is explained by which model?"}, {"answers": ["Leveling off", "Decreasing", "Increasing and decreasing", "Increasing"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Compared to long-term growth patterns, population growth rates since the 1960s have been doing what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "We are expected to reach a population of 8 billion in fewer years than it took for Earths population to move from 6 billion to 7 billion."}, {"answers": ["Ehrlich and Holdren", "Malthus and Boserup", "Holdren and Hartmann", "Ehrlich and Kuznets"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which theorists developed the I = PAT equation?"}]

quizCollection['2'] = quiz
console.log("hi")